<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
      <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                  <titleStmt>
                        <title>The teachings of W.D. Muhammad</title>
                        <author>Wallace Deen Muhammad</author>
                        <editor>Ilyes Mechentel</editor>
                  </titleStmt>
                  <publicationStmt>
                        <distributor>
                              WDM Publications (c)
                        </distributor>
                  </publicationStmt>
                  <sourceDesc>
                        <recordingStmt>
                              <recording type="audio">
                                    <respStmt>
                                          <resp>Enregistré par</resp>
                                          <name>Leslie Taha</name>
                                    </respStmt>
                              </recording>
                        </recordingStmt>
                  </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
            <profileDesc>

                  <particDesc>
                        <listPerson>
                              <person xml:id="PM">
                                    <persName>Prophète Muhammad</persName>
                              </person>
                              <person xml:id="MFM">
                                    <persName>Maître Fard Muhammad</persName>
                              </person>
                              <person xml:id="ComCart">
                                    <persName>Le délégué Cartwright</persName>
                              </person>
                              <person xml:id="RevRA">
                                    <persName>Le révérend Ralph Abernathy</persName>
                              </person>
                              <person xml:id="BroBB">
                                    <persName>Le frère Ben Branch</persName>
                              </person>
                              <person xml:id="MA">
                                    <persName>Muhammad Ali</persName>
                              </person>
                              <person xml:id="POTUS_C">
                                    <persName>Président Jimmy Carter</persName>
                              </person>
                              <person xml:id="SecVance">
                                    <persName>Secrétaire Cyrus Vance</persName>
                              </person>
                              <person xml:id="RabP">
                                    <persName>Rabbin Mayer Perlmuter</persName>
                              </person>
                        </listPerson>
                  </particDesc>

                  <settingDesc>
                        <listPlace>
                              <place xml:id="Arabia">
                                    <placeName>Arabie</placeName>
                              </place>
                              <place xml:id="EU">
                                    <placeName>Europe</placeName>
                              </place>
                              <place xml:id="Chicago">
                                    <placeName>Chicago</placeName>
                              </place>
                              <place xml:id="Det">
                                    <placeName>Detroit</placeName>
                              </place>
                              <place xml:id="NY">
                                    <placeName>New York</placeName>
                              </place>
                              <place xml:id="Philly">
                                    <placeName>Philadelphie</placeName>
                              </place>
                              <place xml:id="LA">
                                    <placeName>Los Angeles</placeName>
                              </place>
                              <place xml:id="USA">
                                    <placeName>États-Unis d'Amérique</placeName>
                              </place>
                              <place xml:id="Africa">
                                    <placeName>Afrique</placeName>
                              </place>
                              <place xml:id="ChiSS">
                                    <placeName>South Side</placeName>
                                    <note>Quartier sud de Chicago</note>
                              </place>
                        </listPlace>
                  </settingDesc>
            </profileDesc>
      </teiHeader>
      <text>
            <body>
                  <div type="audio" n="1">
                        <head>World Community of Islam in the West</head>

                        <p> My Dear Brothers and Sisters: In this article. I will be speaking to you on the purpose,
                              the aim, and the goal in this community called the World Community of Islam in the West.
                        </p>

                        <p>Let us begin with the term "purpose." Our purpose is the revival and the restoration, of pure Islam.
                              When we speak of reviving Islam, we are referring to the kind of teachings or the kind of preachings
                              that were done by many, many Muslims since the days of Prophet Muhammad of
                              <placeName ref="#Arabia"> Arabia </placeName> to bring the Muslim community back to the
                              everyday practical teachings in Islam.
                        </p>

                        <p> In <placeName ref="#USA">America</placeName>, our community began with the teachings of
                              <persName ref="#MFM">"Master Fard Muhammad"</persName>. When we say "Master" we mean "teacher."
                              In <placeName ref="EU">Europe</placeName>, we find that heads of departments of education or
                              schoolteachers are still called schoolmaster today. It is important in Islam to understand
                              the difference between the title teacher and the title reverend. In my contact with a Christian
                              teacher who was one of the first to be called "pastor." he brought my attention to the
                              difference between the title reverend and the title pastor. He said he preferred to be called
                              pastor. Reverend puts stress on the requirement or the need to respect or to revere the person
                              wearing that title. Using the term teacher suggests the giving of knowledge to others and
                              knowledge dignifies those who truly possess it.
                        </p>


                        <div type="audio" n="2">
                              <head>New World Patriotism Day Address</head>

                              <p>Thank you <persName ref="#ComCart">Commissioner Cartwright</persName>. On this great day
                                    here in <placeName ref="#Chicago">Chicago</placeName>, I want first to express my thanks
                                    to Almighty God for inspiring the good elements of our human life to get together within
                                    ourselves and to get together among ourselves as Brothers and Sisters—as citizens of
                                    <placeName ref="#Chicago">Chicago</placeName> and citizens of the world—as human beings
                                    who want to make <placeName ref="#Chicago">Chicago</placeName> a home for all of us
                                    and who want to make this Earth a home for all of us.
                              </p>

                              <p>Like the <persName ref="#RevRA">Honorable Reverend Ralph Abernathy</persName> and
                                    <persName ref="#BroBB">Brother Ben Branch</persName>, I too know that God has given
                                    us the sunshine, and as long as we are coming together for the common good of all
                                    people—for the unification of the  good elements of our lives and for the unification
                                    of the <placeName ref="#Chicago">City of Chicago</placeName>—I know that nothing
                                    bad is going to happen to us.
                              </p>

                              <p>I've been in many countries too, like <persName ref="#MA">Muhammad Ali</persName>, the
                                    World Champion, and believe me, this nation is worshiped and envied all over the world.
                                    Many people resent the greatness of this country, but most people where I've been
                                    outside the <placeName ref="#USA">United States</placeName> are looking to
                                    <placeName ref="#USA">America</placeName> for something to happen that's going to make
                                    things right all around the globe.
                              </p>

                              <p>In <placeName ref="#Africa">Africa</placeName> there's a great test for
                                    <placeName ref="#USA">America</placeName>. We have in <persName ref="#POTUS_C">President
                                    Carter</persName> a morally courageous Administration. Many in the
                                    <placeName ref="#USA">United States</placeName> are not enough in tune with what's
                                    happening around the world, especially in <placeName ref="#Africa">Africa</placeName>,
                                    to really appreciate the moral courage of <persName ref="#POTUS_C">President Carter</persName>,
                                    <persName ref="#SecVance">Secretary Vance</persName> and others in this Administration.
                              </p>

                              <div type="audio" n="3">
                                    <head>Prophethood and Brotherhood</head>

                                    <p> Thank you, <persName ref="#RabP">Rabbi Perelmuter</persName>. It is indeed a great
                                          pleasure and privilege for me and my congregation to be invited to this great
                                          Jewish synagogue to address you in the spirit of brotherhood.
                                    </p>

                                    <p> A few years ago, our ghettos in <placeName ref="#Chicago">Chicago</placeName>,
                                          <placeName ref="#Det">Detroit</placeName>, <placeName ref="#NY">New York</placeName>,
                                          <placeName ref="#Philly">Philadelphia</placeName>. <placeName ref="#LA">Los Angeles</placeName>
                                          and in all the big cities were so burdened, troubled, and confused that I felt
                                          this world was about to be destroyed. Not with physical fire, but with the fire
                                          of spiritual drunkenness, with the fire of racial hatred and ignorance.
                                    </p>

                                    <p>I thank Almighty God for bringing relief to our community and turning the minds
                                          and changing the attitudes of the people and law enforcement. The people now have
                                          a good spirit, a spirit of humanness, a moral spirit is stirring in the people.
                                          There is also moral influence and moral willpower given to us from the top of
                                          the country in the great <persName ref="#POTUS_C">President Carter</persName>
                                          whom I respect and love very dearly.
                                    </p>

                                    <p>We thank Allah, for this great change in this country, the change of spirit and
                                          return to moral consciousness. I myself, have experienced a relief on
                                          <placeName ref="ChiSS">the South Side</placeName>, a relief from subtle mischief-making
                                          of the police department and criminal gangs.
                                    </p>
                              </div>
                        </div>
                  </div>
            </body>
      </text>
</TEI>
